hey guys so let's solve for x in this
equation it has an absolute value inside
of an absolute value this should be fun
the way to get rid of this outer
absolute value is we can take the stuff
inside and set it equal to 16 because if
all this stuff inside is equal to 16
then this will be a true statement we
can also take this inside stuff and set
it equal to negative 16. because if this
stuff inside here is negative 16 this
will also be true so now we have two
equations but we've managed to get rid
of that outer absolute value that's how
we get rid of absolute value signs we
take whatever was inside of them and set
equal to the positive or the negative of
what it's equal to so to get this alone
I'm going to subtract 3x from both sides
so left hand side is just going to be
negative absolute value of x and this
right hand side is going to be 16 minus
3x then I'm going to divide both sides
by negative 1. left hand side is just
the absolute value of x right hand side
will be negative 16 plus 3x let's do the
same thing to this one down here let's
subtract 3x from both sides the
left-hand side is negative absolute
value of x equals and this will be
negative 16 minus 3x divide both sides
by negative 1 and we get absolute value
of x on this side on this side we get 16
plus 3x so we're going to take both of
these equations and split each of them
up into two different equations take
this inside X and we're going to set it
equal to this negative 16 plus 3x we're
also going to take this inside X and set
it equal to the negative of this which
would be positive 16 minus 3x same thing
here we take the X out and set it equal
to that 16 plus 3x and we take the X out
and set equal to the negative of that
which is negative 16 minus 3x for both
these two equations let's subtract 3x
from both sides so the left-hand side is
going to be negative 2X and then for
this side we just bring down the 16 or
bring down the negative 16. divide
everything by negative 2 and this one
becomes x equals 8 and this one becomes
x equals negative 8. and on this side we
can add 3x to both sides of both these
equations X Plus 3x is equal to 4X these
cancel so we bring down the 16 and these
cancel so we bring down the negative 16.
divide everything by 4 and we get x
equals 4 or x equals negative 4. now we
have four possible solutions to try
let's get rid of all this work let's
make these larger and then bring them up
so now I'm going to plug each of these
values in for X the H the 4 the negative
8 and the negative 4. 3 times 8 is 24
absolute value of 8 is 8 24 minus eight
is sixteen absolute value of 16 is equal
to 16 so this one's good 3 times 4 is 12
absolute value 4 is 4 12 minus 4 is 8
absolute value of 8 is 8 8 does not
equal 16 this one's no good 3 times
negative 8 is negative 24 absolute value
of negative 8 is positive eight negative
24 minus 8 is negative 32. absolute
value of negative 32 is positive 32 32
does not equal 16. 3 times negative 4 is
negative 12 absolute value of negative 4
is equal to four negative 12 minus 4 is
negative 16 absolute value of negative
16 is positive 16. 16 16 does equal 16
so x minus 4 is another solution so
these are the two solutions and here's
all the work again how exciting if you
guys want to try more of these I have
this page on andymath.com the link is
down below in the description check it
out and let me know if you have any
other questions I'll happily take
requests